# Tarikua Babore

(240)347-5655 | Baboretarikua@gmail.com | Clarkston, Georgia

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Detail-oriented problem solver with 21 weeks training and experience in Web development. Interested in attaining a career that will allow me the opportunity to excel as a web developer as well as highlight my previous work experience and leadership abilities.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap

- Unit Testing with Mocha
- Git
- XML
- Performance Testing with Hp load runner

## **EXPERIENCE**

- Participating in an 21 weeks, 350+ hours Junior Web Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application
- Learning fundamentals of JavaScript, programming fundamentals, developer tools, git and problem solving

### MJMorgan group | Takoma park, MD | June 2018 - March 2021

HR Assistant

- Maintained positive relationships with candidates and team.
- Answered more than 50 calls a day from new employees, former employees and current employees.
- Assisted with the recruitment process by identifying candidates, performing reference checks, and issuing employment contracts.
- Maintained digital and electronic records of employees

### IMET construction | Addis Abeba, Ethiopia | september 2015- Nov 2016

Site Engineer

- Reviewed work schedules and delegated work tasks
- Planned and prepared technical drawings and construction layouts
- Gathered data and wrote site reports and other necessary work documentations
- Took immediate corrective action to avoid any effect and recover the delay to finish the task in due time
- Attended coordination meetings organized by client and consultants

### **EDUCATION**

Generation Junior Web Developer Program | Feb 2023- July 2023 Bluetech solution performance Testing | April 2022- July 2022 Hawassa university, Ethiopia | June 2015

Bachelor of Civil Engineering